For today's date and time,
call the order of the meeting,
item 2 is public input and schedule personal experiences
only on it's that wishes to address the council on any of the
agenda items.
There being none, item 3 is consent agenda.
Staff is recommending items 4 through the 13
for the consent agenda.
Please take a quick look at those,
and if there are no questions on any of those items,
entertain a motion.
We'll go ahead and check the number of the
questions.
Okay.
So we have a motion to approve.
We have a second.
Second.
Roll call please.
Johnson.
Aye.
Mr.
Weston.
Aye.
I'm 14.
This health care insurance proposal for
in Georgian Roy and stop being in
Georgian's name on it.
Come on out Georgian.
How are you tonight?
Good.
So Georgians aware that this is a discussion item tonight.
We're not taking the action.
Vicki's out sick and it's important.
I think that all council members have their voice heard on this.
You all will see the some information from Georgian.
I don't give you a chance to comment in a minute.
But basically this issue evolved as Georgian and
our family found themselves without insurance.
And so we had a conversation.
She deemed Ben and I about her relationship with
the city and her question was through that relationship.
Are there any opportunities for me to participate in the city's health insurance plan?
And we discussed different things.
No commitments made or of any sort.
And we left the meeting asking Georgian to basically send me a proposal.
Which is outlined in your packet.
And for discussion.
So I'm going to have any comments you want to make before we get into discussion.
Georgian or.
Well, none other than the fact that.
I mean, I think.
I made my proposal in the letter.
A couple of options.
I'll let.
I guess Ben comments on.
Perhaps which one of those is preferable at this point.
I think.
It.
Well.
It's pretty self explanatory.
I think so.
Okay.
So.
I know there was a lot on the agenda tonight.
I don't know if everybody had a chance to read through.
The information.
Perfect.
Okay.
So.
It's really.
First, I guess.
Kind of a philosophical issue.
Of course we have other contract employees.
I'm.
health insurance provided to them as part of their contractual relationship.
Now, the one distinction is, Ben and I talked about, is that they are salary individuals.
They have a set amount each year that they contract for, and they get a salary for that,
and also get consideration in the form of health insurance.
Glenn may do his little bit differently, I think, Glenn chooses to have a salary difference
and pay his for tax reasons, but basically, it's the same, they just choose individuals
to treat the access or how it's paid for a little bit differently.
George Andrew relationship with us has started out, basically, in an hourly rate of $150 an hour,
and there's some information about the number of hours that she's worked for the city
in the last year, and then kind of what she contemplates this year.
Based on conversations that she and Dean has had, and my suggestion to George Ann was that if the council
entertained the idea that it would be, one way would be a reduction in her hourly rate
to offset the employee cost, the other would be providing her access, but she would have to pay for that access.
That's what I want to check for, basically, instead of us paying her last.
But whatever methodology you use, you still have the philosophical question of, how do we treat
contract employees as a whole and access to health insurance?
And I think the example I use was, and we're not currently using anybody to know the review
part, we don't think we are.
I think we eliminate that content, but if we were to use someone for that person be eligible
to go on the cities insurance.
And so, how do you carve that out to you, you classify professional services differently?
And I don't know, that's why it's on the agenda is for everybody kind of voice their thoughts,
maybe he concerns you might have, and then have time to think about it before we consider
action on it.
I want to hear what I'm going to say first, I'd like to say as I hope that you all, as the board
here are pleased with the way that things are going as far as being able to get through the legal
department.
I think Georgian is a great asset to what we're doing, I know recently she found something
that we've been doing that escaped me and escaped apparently several.
my predecessors that we were not necessarily getting what we were thinking we were going
to get. And Kudos to George Anne for finding that we'll get that square away at another
time. But I think that demonstrates the value that she is giving to the city just hoping
that you always see that. You have the options that she's outlining. They aren't exclusive,
but they are the reasonable suggestions. And from my perspective, I think treating her as
a place is the better way to go for a couple of reasons. I don't know exactly what questions
you all might have as far as specifics go.
I concur on how she doesn't bring it down. That's my concern. And I would like this to
say to the mayor the other day, this kind of sprung up on us and we've not necessarily had a chance
to think about this. I mean, I can tell you my initial guidance thing is that going forward with
future contracting, the recovery contract may be an issue. I mean, I would even want to do this
for every contracting bullet. That's my concern. So let me say it, but I think you're saying
another way. It's not so much as you have a concern that I'm doing it with or for George Anne,
but the setting the precedent for down the road and the implications of that. So Kim, could you come up
with us? Because I apologize. I had three different times thought, I need to call Kim and ask her about
the or health plan and how it might be viewed and I just didn't get it done. So how do you see this impacting
our health plan?
She's a contractor. She's a contractor. What Chuck, Glenn, and Ben are our city contractors. So we're
talking about something totally different. Our health plan right now does not allow for us to cover
anyone that is not an eligible employee or dependent. So to cover George Anne and not be a city employee
would mean that we would have to change our health plan. I related to being the same concern.
That would open us up in the future.
We deal with a lot of contractors.
We have contractors all over the building right now,
and in a lot of different ways.
If the council decides to do this with Georgian,
the best way to do it within our health plan,
or in document, it's just like we do with when
and try that we would have contractor.
If not, we have to do them at the health plan.
And we can do that.
And that the concern is what that would open up in the future.
So if we were confident that we had,
and I'm just going to use around number 30 hours,
a month of work for Georgian,
and we contracted with her on a salary basis,
based on what it had, we arrived at the hourly rate.
But then she ended up working twice as many hours
as her way to compensate her for that outside of the contract.
So we would say, we're contracting for a base rate of hours,
and anything over and above that will be,
so the base rate is that rate,
anything over that will be paid at Y rate.
And there are again a dean of breakdown of all the different classes,
because as you all know,
what we input and what we pay is totally different.
Right.
So we're talking about, you know, if we're talking about her being a contractor
and changing the health plan document,
then obviously what it's going to cost her is going to be much more expensive,
because she's not an employee and we don't have that one.
I did provide dean with some details and numbers
depending on which way you decide to go.
Then I could give you those hard numbers as to what that would be.
There's a lot of variables.
There's also other issues.
Life insurance is part of it.
When we do a utility discount,
I can tell you for some of our contract employees
we do.
It's in their contracts up and down.
We offer dental vision and then some supplemental life insurance
and athletic.
But that's outside of that.
Something that the employee would pay for additionally.
So if she was a contractor and not an employee,
but provide that, there's just some things we've got to look out
depending on which way you like it.
So the numbers that were presented in regards to 700,
that was based off of mimicters.
What you're saying on a contractor,
that could take that number extremely high.
Which one totally?
The thing is that you have you would want spouse coverage
and it would probably go, okay.
So in that case,
If she was a sitting boy and was just paying for the family coverage
It would cost her a 44525 mark like any other sitting boy because we don't charge it out of free
If she was paying the premium plus the family it would cost her $1,085 and $20.25
Now what our TPA actually
You know there's a difference between what the TPA says it's costing us each year
You budget so if we went up to that there would be a little bit of an additional cost there
But it's it would be right around 1,085
Depending on the difference probably closer to 12
I'll talk a lot of questions. So Kim I'm not used to this in example. Okay, let's continue to have young kids
So
The city pays approximately 700 on your behalf
Right, and if you then opted for family coverage
It would cost you out of your pocket another 445
And so
That's where you come up with the 1100 and something dollars. I will tell you that something we're looking at as we have not increased for quite a few years
The cost has and what we're paying the employee is paying on the payment coverage
So in the next few years that is something is part of everything we're doing on health care
Look at so that could in the next few years don't a little bit fine. That's the right right now, but next you might be 500 or 550 or whatever
So I mean a hundred ways to skin that financial cat if the counsel chose to proceed
One way would be the reduction error rate that there's an example for a period of time with
George and paying the difference which is what other employees do now
That's right
I don't think any of us are
Interested in that option
Right, and that's why we won't do come up so we can understand
Not ramifications of everything if math was never my best subject, but I'm sitting here if I if we if we look at what your proposal was and you said 1718 hours
It would you current rate was you would bump that up to 28 and drop it down
120 by
We would pay more than to the year for your services
Correct, so I mean we're looking at an additional cost at the city for another 10 to out
I just want to make sure
Well, and to your point, we're not, we would not in any way be guaranteeing George and a single hour.
These numbers are based on these expectations over the next year.
The 28 hours, I think, because in our conversation, Dean had some different projects,
and he anticipated, he hadn't been displayed in George F.
But there's no guarantee of any help.
At least there's not like me.
So, and to give you just, when you're wondering about what projects you,
you know what projects you're going to keep right now.
We have about a four, four, a half million dollar project,
and we have a really double-digital sub-digital.
That's going to take a lot of contractual documents.
We didn't have something like George F.
We're not going to have to find somebody who helps with that.
And he's very deep in the documents.
We're about to do less info.
All the utilities there.
I don't need to const and the contract.
So, in those cases, we're probably going to ask you some end acquisitions.
We're probably going to ask you some wide of way of acquisitions.
I think such as that, the same might maybe be true,
but what's taking place on which we're in first street and fourth street on Main Street,
because other people there who have those issues that come up.
Along that line, what we're doing in the community,
the bottom of the bottom of the piece.
You have several items that we do right now,
are from the documents to the beats that take place in the community.
As some of the community, that's going to make sure it's got a problem.
So, we're becoming less more active,
and when it comes to that type of issue,
plus the fact that we're getting very clear about right now,
technical and remote.
We have some utility projects that are going to be extending
to the east for some potential economic development activities.
You're going to have to have contracts on that as well.
So, as I said, I think we're going to be very active,
and I don't think it's sometimes might be a little slow,
and sometimes you might just be pedal to them now,
but I think all those are kind of the average efforts that we're going to be needing.
So, we're successful.
We're going to have to.
Please.
Thank you.
And I think this is known by everyone,
but just to reiterate that my,
it's not lost on me that we're talking about my own contracts,
and I am the attorney for the city to refuse the city's contract.
So, this is why not, obviously,
but if this were not me and you were talking about,
I would be, you know, telling you all,
you probably ought to pick the simplest thing that achieves
this.
cities objectives. Obviously, it's the cities interest that have to be considered first.
I have them to think there's a possibility of a mutually beneficial relationship.
And of course, I see this, I hope, this is a long-term working relationship.
I have been, as I told Rudy and being a man, I have been delightfully surprised at how much
I came into this, with essentially no expectations, no good expectations, no bad expectations.
But I have been delightfully surprised at the fashion all of the people that I have worked with
across city staff. I mean, it's really, well, it's just refreshing.
It makes this work very enjoyable. I know that sounds like a kind of shrews and hate.
But it's just true. The truth is cheesy, the truth is cheesy, but I do appreciate this opportunity.
And I do hope that it is a long-term one. So to the extent that that being said anything.
And I think you won't have this, but just to mention, any language contracts I would be by talking about.
So even when we get this contract, he wasn't involved in that. We have a label which I'm going to answer out.
And that's the secret of the way that he works with.
How to do your homework?
Yeah, I'm not saying it, but I think I assume that.
I think you should know what you call that.
Any more conversation tonight?
I'm going to talk about the right now.
I do want to ponder it. And I think Dean will be, you know, I'll be waiting for your suggestion
in your recommendation on this as well. But I think we should, you know,
we've got valuable employees. We've got investment in them because, I mean, as a city, we're trying to
move forward and trying to accomplish a lot of things. And that's what we need.
So I agree with Doug. And I'm going to think about some things.
You know, one of the things always stands out to me is that whenever we talked about a band and a shock
and glance, one of the things, you know, it's just, how do you handle evaluation on that?
So that's, I'm just trying to figure out with this. How do we evaluate this?
Whether that's you or how do we feel, or I just want to make sure that for the city's sake,
that, you know, we're getting what we want. I just want to see,
trying to get, I need to run my numbers a little better and kind of understand that before I get that.
You know, one of the things you mentioned, that was one thing always to keep in mind,
it's a legal service. So it's a really good review of the council. You have to have a fireball.
We're very well together.
You've got that firewall because the answer is to you.
Why answer to you?
You want to have that type of check-in balance.
I think of a decision like this.
This is very similar.
Where you want to be sure that you have that check-in balance
as to what?
Any of the four attorneys or even five attorneys
when you talk about something like 20, 20, 20.
So make sure whatever recommendation work regarding contracts
and all that, I think you've done it for review, not for me,
that's usually important.
I want to appreciate that, Ben.
I think, no, it's point is that you guys are the ones
and the trenches every day when it'd be at Georgetown
or being at the back, we're not us.
And so it'll feedback from you guys as important to us.
Okay.
Thank you, George.
Thank you.
Thanks, Kim.
Okay.
There's going to be no action on agenda item 14.
Item 15 is award bid number 1833 and amount of 16931
to try state trucks in for roll off truck, Tyler and Kevin.
It's your 24.
It's just where they roll off.
It's been approved in the budget.
Okay.
We'll just ask them for your approval.
This is not a roll off container, but an actual truck.
Okay.
And it's replacing what?
Two thousand six.
Starts off.
Okay.
It's roll off truck.
It's worn out.
I'm guessing.
It has over 200,000 miles on it.
It should've got the hours off of it, but I didn't.
It's just what happens with the old one.
We will actually save that truck for a backup.
And kids don't want to just throw down.
Just so we go back up.
Okay.
It needs a lot of work down on it.
As a backup, I think it would be good.
For example, the light bar across the back row.
Which all lights are the rust in now.
You know, I don't think police would let us drive it every day.
Once it's blown off.
I mean, what?
Occasionally?
We're not busy.
That take the lights in.
They're not.
It's a backup.
Okay.
And we got it.
Yeah.
I was like.
No, anyway.
We've used your services at Thermal Fisher.
And there's always been a little concern about overfilling those dumpsters.
Well, this truck handle a little more weight so we can fill it up.
It's the height here.
You gotta stay at the top of the highway.
I thought we were pretty good, but...
Yeah.
We're good.
You're good.
Okay.
All right.
I just want to remind you that this is on a earlier agenda.
And we ask you to take the other.
We're both a better panel.
Right.
So it seems familiar.
That's why I had this official.
Okay.
Any other questions?
We have a motion.
Yeah.
I got one thing.
And I got to say this way.
I visited with him briefly because in regards to the two different quotes, one of them quotes is different
because of the apparatus that they're going to use to serve us and grease their trucks.
So when somebody sees it or anybody's bored that they're going through our paperwork and checking it,
and why we went with tri-state is a lot of it was due to a preventing maintenance apparatus that's going to install on trucks.
I just spoke to Kevin briefly before the meeting and said, you know, the one thing that I've only requested to do is to stay with his guys that are working on this.
And keep up with it.
And kind of see how it is for the future for the other equipment.
Just so you can make sure.
We do a monthly check on all of our equipment.
I have one person with every month.
They have to be an entire truck.
Check it out.
That's not going to change because we're getting the problem with the system on this truck.
And it's just one of those things that I just, it can make somebody that, if they think it's working right there,
and that's my button and it's doing its thing.
I don't have to call it or anything.
Even though we're inspecting, I'm going to just make sure that they stay on it.
So you don't have a problem down the road.
Let's see what we can think.
But that is why the price difference in what you with it.
Okay.
That's all I go.
I'll make a motion.
We'll follow.
For Mr. Johnson.
All right.
Wester.
Thank you.
I am 16-camera.
We're going to venture government relations this simple January claim of 6000.
So I think this came in the last month's claim from capital ventures came in and just missed the deadline.
And so we didn't have a second meeting in the second.
Mr. Jackson.
This was held over.
And then we had a January claim in right now that we're normally kind of on the first council meeting.
That's why it's basically December of danger.
But after this meeting, then it will start showing them on your first meeting.
And then.
I don't know what's going to happen.
Then what recent communication that we had with him with respect to work he's doing for us on our street issue.
Well, he's still working on that street issue.
He should get it on to the eight-year plan.
Especially in regard to Steve O'Leard.
And still trying to get some work done on reviving 2020.
He's also started to give us some assistance.
on the risk of that item has been kind of formed for a little while, but we've been
put this in touch with the number of people with the EPA and that project is probably
they started in a very simple. And then finally the other issue that he's been held in
as part of that, we're going to be talking about it in our second session, are some of the issues
related to the responses with the firm. And some discussions with some of the more legislative
delegations in the West, so those are the key issues he's been working with himself.
All right, so do we have a motion to approve item 16, make a motion. And a second, second,
a little help. Forster, Western, Johnson, Schultz. Hi. Thank you, item 17. There's not
a minute to appoint that killer to the MDRE authority, replacing the rather Robinson,
in terms of expire 829 of 2021. Mr. Keller is someone that Neil brought to my attention and lives
in his reward and works at the hospital. And we're ready to do many years of service to our community.
It's just trying to find kind of play with the grandkids and travel a little bit. So she has resigned
from the board and we need to replace her. And so I'm putting Matt's name before you.
Like you said, maybe better work hospitalization is a good man.
I've got a great lot to put a nice person. I'm going to be playing with my office.
We're going to do a good job. Now I can motion to approve your item.
Okay. Do we have a second? A little second.
Roll call please. Johnson, Western, forster. All right. Thank you, item 18, orange, 20, 1801.
Mending title chapter, the title chapter 16 from Parks and Rec and a Mending or two Parks and Rec
creation and a Mending or appealing all sections and then relating the cemeteries and over JAR by deleting
such references and creating chapter 28 cemeteries, setting out there and all the ordinance. So in effect,
if I can summarize him, basically taking the JAR cemeteries, setting it up is its own department.
So to speak, out for one of Parks and Rec. So I think you guys have some questions.
So I'm just going to give you a brief summary of how this came about. What we're talking about
to know is changes in the ordinance, changes in the JAR rules and regulations and then the regular
groups. So three different things that are grouped together. We've been working on this project for
layout over a year. Nancy, grow, or office manager and then have been so helpful and done a great job
on this. We had a small break and rules change in December 2014, but we have not had any kind of an increase,
the only increase since October of 2004. We surveyed and got one.
three responses from the Cemetery is all over within a 200 mile radius of us and that is where
we came up with our cork and average. We believe they're very changing the region,
right somewhere between 25 to 30 percent in a Greece revenue yearly. The ordinance change came
about because in September of 2016 the parks and red board merged with the CDB board and at that
time that came up in a staff meeting, it was on a council agenda and I said what about GAR? What are
we going to do? And we have the discussion at that time that because GAR is no longer part of the
parks department. But probably more than anything else, the discussion we have was that the focus
of the parks and red and CDB board was more about tourism and, you know, Dean and I discussed
the Cemetery didn't really fit into kind of the new purpose of that. And so the correctant was
that we needed to go ahead and get the updates and the ordinances and in our rules because
it has reflected that we were under the parks and the fact that we haven't been in September of 2016.
Just one more thing, one of the reasons that I kind of hesitate on what our revenue will be in 2008,
86% of the burials we did were regular burials. 14% will commence either ons or ashes. This year
today, 69% are regular burials and 31% are ons and ashes and that number just keeps going up and up.
What that means for us is we're doing, having less opening and closing, we're selling less plots
for regular burials. What we're doing to offset that is we're opening a new section this year,
a new baby section and as part of that, it's called the government angels. We'll have a
angel statue in the middle. We'll have quite a few earned plots just to try to kind of open up another
possibility for families and also to generate that revenue. In this cemetery industry, the same thing
has happened. You can actually encounter more in most areas. It's like over 80% are remains.
So that's the only reason I hesitate a little bit on our revenue because I don't know how much that's
going to change. But right now we projected, we bring in 74,500 dollars this year and we are right
at 50% when 33,410 is what we've taken in and then of course $3800 when you add that to it. That's the 25%
of any plots, anything we sell in the Muslim land that goes into our perpetual care fund.
So you're 33,000 years just don't halfway through the year. Right. So the budget wise you're not off budget,
necessarily if you are just a little bit. Can you embed your wealth that you're a care fund?
because I was able to use the child in doubt,
which I didn't know was a really quiet lie,
but if no one was buried, the GAR, again, starting tomorrow,
for the next 50 years,
because there's sufficient funds to take care of what's there.
So, GAR's unique, we do have a perpetual care fund,
national code, the cemetery, man.
State law does not require us to have a perpetual care fund
because we are a not-for-profit municipal cemetery,
but we still do, and we just workly always have.
For accounting purposes, we have to have
for audit purposes, the cemetery.
And we choose to put a 25% into that.
We could do less than that.
We could do 12%, which at one time...
12 and a half.
12 and a half, I'm sorry.
But we chosen to go higher than that,
because we know those are the funds
that are going to continue to care, re-scenting.
This year, when I talk about opening the new section,
the funds are coming out of perpetual care.
Usually, if we have roads, it has to be things
that are inside that fence.
It has to be things that are roads.
We've used it before in the water system,
we have water issues sometimes.
The busybo is built out of perpetual care.
We bought a common variant for national transportation.
We used, if you remember, now you're probably four or five years ago,
we used quite a bit out of it to pave 11 roads on the south end.
The old part of the cemetery that had never had any kind of paved road.
And that was the number one complaint we got when people on that end
is why don't we have nice roads like everyone else.
We plan through the years to maybe do one or two years
to try to make it all the way to the back.
And then everywhere, the JRPG.
So do you know roughly what that fund balances?
Right now it is $153,420.
So the sense idea is that the right issues are really a big concern.
Some of the policy changes are really a big concern.
The big concern is that this was moved out from under the parks department
without a discussion and not part of the parks.
We were dying in discussion with the parks.
We were at least as the perception.
And so I don't know how necessarily you guys want that addressed.
But that's a lot for you.
I had a question.
You might not be at the answer.
That's fine.
Yeah.
How many straight studies?
I don't know.
We've got a 25, 25, 25, that you check.
We're a week-fall in the 25 will be kind of in the middle of the road, as far as the right
road.
That's what we call it.
Before these recommended changes, we were rock bottom on almost everything, really, really
loud.
We probably could count to you for an increase higher, but we feel like we're not a
non-corrupted cemetery.
We want to be able to serve our families and we are not the wealthiest candy in
up on them.
But we still need to be able to cover some of our costs.
Our yearly budget is at $38,000 to $88,000, 85% of our stores in hell.
12% is materials, and 3% is other services, and so we just feel like anything that
we generate in revenue that is very market-ready is many of the cemeteries not taking
from the general fund.
And this is going to bring us a little closer from the minimum to the mid-point for most
centers.
Delay, here you say 25% is what you're expecting.
When was the last time we had a rate increase for them before?
And how much was that?
At that time, I didn't know that I can, well, if I remember correctly, it was like 3% of
the cost of war.
Okay, so is that spread evenly, I guess, if you will, for great openings, and as far as the
crumines, I mean, I know that's an upward trend, it seems like, because of cost, everyone's
migrating to that type of feeling.
You'll notice that one of the things that we increased, when we do things dealing with
ashes, we only charged $75.
We had to increase that a little bit, I mean, we still have to have staff.
We have to be there with the family, so there's still an offset in cost.
You'll look on this list.
It's going to show you what our current rates are.
The middle is what we're recommending is the increase.
Is that an increase on top of the curve?
Or is that what it's going to be?
That's what it's going to be.
Okay, that's what I want to make.
Yes.
And then off on the very end, and that last column shows you the average of the 22.
And when we say 23, it's because we included ourselves in this.
It shows the average.
I will point out to you, this was just a sheet for everyone to kind of have a reference.
There is one type of, the mayor of part down at the very end, where it's a distant
term.
It says 1477.
That's actually $1,000.
But in the actual Wilson Raves and in the ordinance, everything is correct.
So this was just a reference sheet for all of you.
That's the one that kind of stood out to me, because it was such a drastic increase.
I mean, I know when you look at your average 22, it's right where it needs to be.
But that is a big, is that something to do?
So we do average from one to three distant term that's a year.
And the distant term that's are very time intensive.
Sometimes they can take all day.
We have to have staff there.
There's a whole process.
We have to follow.
So you're not only digging up a vault.
Then you have to rebarrivolve in a lot of cases.
It's just so time-intensive, it's why it's so expensive.
Well, those typically are a family asking, because I really want to relocate it as a
legal issue.
It's all over the board, and it's part of what we have to do.
I can tell you, those aren't happy saves for us, or even no one likes that.
Sometimes they want to move them in another part of the cemetery, and we have people that
have bought a family plot, and somebody was buried in 1970, and they want them with everyone else.
We think we're going to have one in the next month or two where a family has hired a private
pathologist, and done everything they need to do.
They want that person, and they want them to be examined.
I've been, since 2009, I've never had a corner situation, but I know we've had a couple
of those in the past where they come in.
It's a lot of different things.
Sometimes they're into other states, and it gets all over the board.
And basically, for this change, as you will, Mayor, it's talked about taking yourself out from
underneath the umbrella of parks, and being underneath that parks board, what is there anything
other than just doing it to, so you guys can be your own entity, because you don't want to consider
yourself tourism, or...
I don't really want to speak to this, but I'll say it was more, I don't think we will want
it.
That one.
Well, and here's what I'm going to say, I would say that is absolutely not my case since I've
been on the CBB board, but I until I read this was unaware, because no one ever attended any
of the meetings that I even knew that cemetery fell underneath it, shame on me, maybe I should.
Well, just before I had the contour about you, then I didn't know about you, about you.
And I want to rephrase that, I don't want to say not one that I would never say that,
I mean, it would never.
It was more when we talked about it that day in staff about what the new direction was at the
board, and that everything was very tourism and recreational parks focused, and I think the conversation
that we all had was, how was the cemetery?
There was just a different mission.
It's a extremely different mission, that's what we were going to do.
Also, it would be very honest, it's what we're doing right now with the cemetery when we have
a cemetery, especially a charter record.
I don't know, please.
Well, although you're not the only one that was staying so interesting, but it's mainly because
you have people with a passion to make sure that everything out there is done correctly.
Just like we had in CBB, it's just like we had in parks, but again, the mission is just so
open for you to get from the types of things that Kim was just talking about, that they
have to deal with.
Really, that's done.
But that, anybody other than the families were full, we're trying to do the CBB in parks, affects
everybody in our community.
So it's just a different mission, isn't there?
And I think.
our chief of police is, as an example, too, with the airport.
I mean, I told Wally, at the other night, I said, we have some really strange combinations
in our city, but it's because we have people that are passionate about certain things that
are willing to wear them more than one hand.
And that's true.
And we're fortunate to have this small community in a small organization, and that's what
we're going to discuss.
I will tell you that we never went to the new parks in CBB more to discuss it.
We did go to parks at the end and had a discussion about how we were no longer going to be
related.
That was right around the time I think it changed, but we never did because of that point,
we didn't think any longer part of that, I guess.
I mean, we were, I mean, I don't have any issue with this concept here, I'm fine with
that.
My partner issue was that me and Brian both served on that board, and I just think, and I don't
want to sit up here and speak to the board.
That's not my job.
I've just done more kind of pull-up this, we're going to come to the board first, to
recommend you to the council.
That's mine.
So, but one thing to keep this said, I've never get up is that when we make the connection with
CBB and parks, this doesn't fall into the council, it doesn't fall into the council, it
doesn't fall into the council.
But I thought it was a courtesy thing to go to them and say, hey, we're going to do that.
I've really enjoyed working with all of you because I really did, I enjoyed working with you.
You said they did make a recommendation or did they do that?
I just thought it was a courtesy to go to them and say, I just want to know that we're not going
to be working together anymore, I appreciate it, what you've done.
B, did you have something to do with that?
I did.
I think you're touching on probably the most significant issue that this, or that brings into consideration,
but there are a few other things that I wanted to point out.
When we were grafting this, we looked at other issues that maybe have not come up here,
but we know that they have come up in other places.
For instance, in reviewing our ordinance as it presently exists, there is no prohibition that
would keep somebody from planning grandma on the backyard in the city of Miami if they wanted to.
With this ordinance, they would not be able to do that, they would have to do it in a, basically,
in a recognized cemetery.
Another example is that the current ordinance has no provisions with regards to a pet cemetery.
Now, it's my understanding, there's no plans on us doing a pet cemetery in the near future, but
that is something that is occurring across the country and, and...
So we needed to have the ability to regulate that another issue that we looked at was protests
at Cemetery's and reviewing the state statute, we actually have a state statute that
addresses that I think in part, it's okay, I think in part it will probably be found
to be unconstitutional based on Supreme Court decisions that have come down, but we chose
not to address that in this ordinance, simply because of somebody's going to be fighting
that fight, we'd rather it be the state of Oklahoma than the city of Miami trying to get
a state statute to be appealed.
So there were several other issues that we have addressed in this that may never come about,
but then they could and so we tried to foresee what we, you know, everything that we could
think of so that we did this as a comprehensive ordinance at the time of doing it.
If such pets cemetery becomes a hot topic and somebody brings this to you and says we want
in our city, we want one in JAR, is that a possibility or no, they can't have it in the same
okay, that's what I want to argue with, okay, it has to be, it has to be a different location,
that's what's just one of one of the things we've done, we've done that through somebody who decided
to do one, you know, they're going to beg it, I think it's your call, probably that we would have said
yeah, that's some say over there, yeah, if you're saying it, probably.
Well, pets cemetery is actually kind of a form, this is the previous main campus, it was interested in that,
and might be back at the time once, we needed everything to kind of take care of JAR,
this is not an anti-pets cemetery, this is not an anti-pets cemetery at all,
but it's just making sure that it's in the right place of life, it's not a lot of things to do,
so what's your pleasure, gentlemen, we want to take this up tonight or do you want to ask him to
brief the CD, CD-B slash Park's Board, and ask him for the next occasion,
next Wednesday, I'm like Neil, I don't have a problem with, I think it's great,
I think it's the separation, there's nothing, I think, just out of it, and I know you've already
done that with the passports, I would just say, I would just, I would throw something together,
and just say this is what we're going to do and I don't think you're going to have a problem with it.
And I talked to the dean about it and I know I think when I read through here that one time
a long time ago, I didn't look at the dates but they're used to be a cemetery board.
You know we're trying to look at reducing boards and I have no problem with this.
It's not like we've been making any discussion about it but I just, for me I would say,
you know, let's work on this next Wednesday at 10 o'clock but then you can have a objection
that everything goes well with the CDB's part of the board and we're bringing it back to you.
We can have a lot of concerns.
You're just absolutely absolutely.
I'm just happy to do that.
I'd be happy to do that.
I think it's like I told the band that I said that.
The way our CDB meetings are in order
marathons anymore and the less we have.
They've just got to that.
I think most of your members will agree with you.
Yeah, I think that's not the issue.
I just want to, I just want the board to be honest.
And the nice thing about what you're talking about the building all for anybody walking in,
even though they're very comfortable boards because it's a lot.
It's just that's what I mean.
Yeah, it's changed since the arts work come on if they're just a lot more to it and I don't think.
And that's okay, yeah.
I'm just trying to be that.
And you know less and more for me if I can handle it appropriately at the time.
So with future we do something like this.
I'll go to that extra step to make sure.
Yeah, it's like you said there was that transition period.
Me and Brian, maybe no idea if we're going on that.
And the other day after that transition, I think our minds said that they're trying to get this done.
We had a lot of that.
You're the remains of what we created.
I think happy sitting down.
Yeah.
Well, this is what you put that on.
Absolutely.
Thank you all.
Thank you.
Okay, I done.
Nineteen.
We need to motion the head of the left.
Or we can just take no action.
And then struck staff to put it on the next council meeting.
Because if we table it ends up there anyway, I don't know if it automatically ends up on the consent agenda,
which is where we want it to sound like that.
Okay.
So let's just direct staff to put it on the next agenda on the consent agenda.
We're doing some amendment in section 27 days three.
rainy day from the chapter 27 by Jean Finatt providing some ability and establishing an effective date.
You know, had been, had been.
So our fingers, let me start with this.
No start with an apology apparently.
What I sent to Melissa for the red line copy that was then sent out to you all was not,
was not accurate.
It had been saved and only part of the changes were reflected there.
So what, we didn't get the last version.
What you did get the last version, but you didn't see all the changes that were being made.
and so I apologize for that. We do have those now and I think what we're contemplating is, again,
discussing this this evening and then coming back and looking at it at a later meeting, probably the next meeting.
There are some policy issues that I don't know that everybody on staff is 100%
sold on, so I mean there's discussion amongst staff on it, but we needed to get this conversation going,
and this is the first that you've seen of this. How this came about to begin with is when we enacted
the budget for this fiscal year that we're currently in, we took some of the money from the rainy day
fund to use for the renovations of the Civic Center. In the actually doing that, we found the
ordinance as it currently exists to be somewhat cumbersome and somewhat uncertain in certain areas,
and so this was an attempt to try to clarify and make it easier to do that from here on out whenever we're
wanting to address the issue of taking money from the rainy day fund. So the draft that you have with you,
I think the two most, and many of the changes are really, I don't consider it to be a great
significance, it's just to clarify a few issues. There are some changes that are somewhat significant
in the final draft that you have, and I want to point those out to you specifically, the first one
is that the current ordinance requires a fourth fifth majority of the council to take money out
in the draft that we have in front of you requires a majority. And the reasoning behind that is
the money going into the fund is done by a majority, not a fourth this. The money that goes
the setting the budget is done by a majority, and this very much is a budget issue as opposed to
any other function that the city does, and so the idea was to have some consistency of it being
the same thing, the majority rule. The other somewhat significant issue.
And this is one of the areas where we had uncertainty in what we did at the setting of this year's fiscal budget.
The mechanism, the actual mechanism of doing it simply was not clear.
This says that it has to be done by warrants.
I think that makes it a more formal process than it just being done by a resolution or just doing it somehow.
It just makes it a little clearer that that's the actual mechanism that we would use in order to accomplish it.
You come out with draws with draws.
And to clarify, however, when you said the budget is approved by simple majority, that could be as few as two people.
Three people would be informed.
So two people, if the day it was only a chance to approve the budget, the same budget for that year,
if only three council members will present two council members will actually actually be sufficient to approve the budget.
I am glad you asked that question because actually in thinking about it, the actual wording in the ordinance as it exists in front of you right now is that it does require a majority of the council.
So I would interpret that as being three.
Okay.
And that means two or three are the least three of five.
I think it will require three of them.
So it's not a majority of the council president, the meeting is a majority of the council.
Correct.
I feel more comfortable with that, I think.
I would also.
Which takes me back to the mother question.
In fact, two members could vote the answer to my three of the president approve the budget.
Is that correct?
That would be correct.
So this is a little bit higher bar.
Pulling the app.
Which I buy?
Yeah.
Okay.
But a mother that's internally, that was one of the reasons why we were talking about the ordinance as well.
This is that kind of bar.
And it also has a record on it.
It will be a very poor instance, because it was a record in the city.
That's important that money out.
Yeah.
If we're at a point where we're asking to do that as for something pretty important.
So being because there was a little bit uncertainty about the language that you just talked about.
Can you make that language even clearer before next meeting?
I mean, just say three or five, whatever.
Whatever language you need.
Let's make it crystal clear.
So that somebody can use them as a one.
I wrote that.
This meeting is two out of three.
If that's all it's there.
We can do that because the the mechanism that we used this year was simply and I forget the name of the document
The certification
Right you got you guys just approved the certification
To somebody that really didn't understand exactly what you were doing it would be hard to figure out that that's what we actually did
Okay, I think I think I think it's obviously the ordinance approach and the majority of the council
Approach
Is there anything else of significance in there, man
Jill anything I think that's the major things. So the twin the next meeting you'll get a revised red line
Include the visual language to make it right and clear that it's a majority of the five
Seven council members what ever there is when that day next time comes it's the majority of the entire
Yeah, the entire council
That may be all you need to do is insert that word
Okay, so we are going to
Take more action on this item and anticipate there will be on the next agenda also and this
Anybody else have any questions or concerns, okay?
item
ordinance
2018 that show three a meeting chapter four animals providing
Servability and establishing an effective date being in the show
Raising the
pickup fee by
$10 in safety if I was going to be 35
We are going to
put that free like if we come and get your nuggets at large and you come pick it up. It's going to cost me 35 dollars
The we're also
Raising the cattle feed it's five dollars a night now
We're going to raise it to $10
Just to try to recoup some of our costs that you know to feed them and and things like that
Is so if you pick up my dog and I come to pick it up the next day. It's going to be $45 to get him out
Okay, okay, okay, I just want to make sure a clarification the 35 doesn't include any
No, each not
No, it would be $45 and then for every night
It has that it is an extra $10
One of the things that this will help us to get some processes in place and things like that
where we get a more uniform way of dealing with things, it's an 18-page ordinance, so...
What have you done?
What have you done in claimed animals?
I'm sorry.
Unclaimed animals.
We do everything that we can to get them adopted out.
At what point?
I mean, how long do you have them there and they become adoptive?
It's a free business.
That gives extremely important that it's business days.
It's not calendar-based.
So if you can't get a dog on Friday and come Monday, adopt it out.
Because those are not business days.
We mean, a lot of people, dogs are tricky little animals.
They have food deemies, they get out, and maybe someone has gone for the weekend.
And you don't intend on it.
I mean, we want to give everybody as much opportunity to get their dog as possible.
That's always a good one-facebook and it means like that now.
We don't want to be the place that comes and gets your dog because someone's called that it's running at large.
And maybe you've gone to Mom's house for the weekend and she lives in Kansas City and come Monday.
Your dog's adopted out because it's a cute little sit-shits.
So we're trying very hard to make sure that everybody's got ample opportunity to come and play with them.
Is that about an average three days? Is that what the kind of...
Yes, it really is. It's about average.
Most people are three days.
It's not three business days.
We're making that just a little bit longer.
I guess some neighbors I wish it was one day.
I don't know.
We've been out there anyway and we keep it.
And that's one of the things too that we're finding out.
We have repeat offenders that their dog gets out.
We pick it up. They pay the money.
And then their dog gets out. We pick it up. They pay the money.
So we're hoping that right now a bit might make them a little more thoughtful of trying to keep their dog in.
So I don't know.
And that's suggesting we change this now.
But if we continue to have repeat offenders,
we may want to change the fees for a third or fourth time.
And they may need to go see the city judge.
Well, there's an offense for letting your dog run at large.
And it's not just dogs.
I mean, for instance, has an owner of goats and parents.
And learning how smart things are.
How smart they are escaping.
It took me some time to figure out how that's an issue.
that we dealt with. Also where I lived in the last month we've had cows at large and we really
get bored Friday. What? A duck. Okay. Anyway, again we tried to envision what issues we might have come
up and to address those and use ordinances. What we, at least when I spent the probably the most
time on was the official animals. And so that was we did plagiarize the heck out of that. Because using
something that's tried to treat is always better than trying to reinvent for all yourself. What
about input from citizenry did we get input from? We had a couple of meetings with people from the
animal welfare society as well as animal rights. We might have that animal rights. We had
bought abortion, just like we tried to make it as workable as you can and still protect everybody's
interest and have to be something that is feasible for the guy on the ground that has to deal
vanishing. So as a sure sense that we were able to accommodate most of their
confound, if not all. I mean there were discussions of other things that would have made this a very
political hot potato that would have filmed this when we put those in. Maybe there's something that we can
work towards at a future date that we kind of envision this as the local bread it's better to
eat at one slice of a time rather than trying to pull off. And are you looking for approval tonight?
Since we've titled the other two or you? And if that is what you want to do, that is great. If you want
to look at it, think about it. You have any concern? I think they've done a great job, but first thing,
I did like the next column I actually call them, but the ordinance as far as giving away puppies and
kittens on the walks. That wasn't one of the things that
they're having.
the committee and the people that did come out and that was kind of half out and worked out
through there. Much to the enjoyment or the betterment for our community and things like
that to get that puppy in the basket often a private parking lot to wear. It ends up in our shelter
and so four days ago when we start to throw in, where they find out, it's a rambunctious puppy
and not just one of those key words that sound the loud.
The chance to get a lot of that.
Thank you.
So in order to, you know, one of the things you touched briefly on, I will get into it deep
as, oh, the vicious animals.
And I think I briefly read through this.
Who constitute? Is that somebody from the city you send out, what you've failed you?
Somebody gives a complaint and says, you know, this is what happens.
Do you go out and determine whether that is vicious?
That is, it sets the criteria, right?
And then gives the public voice director the authority to make that decision now, so it's a beautiful
to court, right?
But it gives us the opportunity to have that decision made.
Okay.
We can make the determination that is the vicious animal now, but at least can write the ticket.
That's fine.
I just want to do it when they contact you and it doesn't say anything about somebody that, you know,
I had somebody that had a concern about an animal, but they're afraid to say anything
because of what might be retaliated against them.
And I said, you know, I don't know if a person can be, if I read this, that person has to stand up and say,
I believe it's vicious.
They can't remain anonymous, can they?
For a person calls?
And I'm just asking you to think about that because I don't even want to say anything, because they're worried about the owners retaliating against them.
So does a, and I think it stands in here that they, if they have to go.
They can't even.
If they call an officer and officer, they're over and see the dog growling by.
But that's to make that determination to be an animal.
They're going to need to take it on their, brought by their operations.
And then it won't be able to be called for anything.
Because the operation operation.
Okay.
And that's fine.
I just want somebody, I just wanted to do a little clarification if somebody has.
There is one of that, and obviously, as long as it's, if it's seen, it has a vision.
Okay.
If an animal does, I do, it's just round of you.
And then it's time to go, you know, and one of them, you know, play best, whatever.
I think you're going to see the fish sand when you have to go.
That would be good.
And the other side of that, of course, is we still wanted to give a pet owner and a animal to write to do.
what we are sometimes wanting them to do, and I'll use myself as an example.
My first batch of goats were all murdered by some erotic dogs, so I now have some dogs
that I anticipate if something were to get in there and try to attack the goats that they would
attack those dogs, but because of a specific exception in here, my dogs would not be considered
vicious animals, because that's what I've got of them, but if an animal just attacks other
dogs, then it could be considered a vicious animal for that.
So we try to balance all of these things out, because we'll give them to help talk about it.
And even though he's got the vicious animal, it doesn't make it.
There are set criteria, he has to abide by, he has to keep that dog in the distance.
So you're not going to let an animal just run loose for any reason whatsoever.
Whether it's the right to stop in the world, a vicious animal, or whatever, it's in here that they can't.
There is a reason.
I haven't checked up on the service dog, what it takes to may have a service dog.
Somebody expressed that it's for a lot of people you could have a service dog.
But do they have exemptions from being vicious because they're labeled a service dog?
Or are they considered in the end or not?
Well, police dogs.
Well, I'm just talking homeowner, it says my dog's a service dog.
Whether he has paperwork or not, I don't.
The problem with the service dog is you could go on the internet and pay your $15.
You'll get a certificate that says you're a fan, right?
It's a service animal.
And it may not be able to do that.
So what we incorporated was the ADA.
In the federal markets with disabilities act, it has a specific provision.
It talks about what really is a service animal.
We incorporate that into this.
But I don't know if they're being a service animal, but it services to that.
No, no, I'm not saying that.
I'm just saying if you have somebody that says it's a service dog, it's vicious.
I didn't know if it gave them a couple of it.
Well, it's going to have to meet the ADA requirements in order for it to actually be.
Because I know of one that seems pretty vicious and all I keep getting told is he's a service dog.
I really don't share it about that part of it.
But I just, you know, and I've had other people in the vicinity question this.
And it's just a topic because why I brought it up.
Okay.
And we've done a little bit of that.
I want to go back to it for.
like all of y'all do we keep track of a little bit you know we do now we didn't
a year ago but each dog that comes in gets a number we go through and and kind of
it's behavior kind of somehow this is how they're doing that way if they're aggressive
if they're aggression it's starting to go down and on the backside of that we'll keep
in track of those and when we start seeing it's kind of a light and start calibrating but we have
a dog that's been there seven or eight or nine months or a year and we start seeing that it's
quality of life is you know we start monitoring that too so we do take we do keep track of
how many animals we come in and we have a spreadsheet and you can go through a filter it and you know
same address we're getting an over and over and over again so one of the requirements if the
animal is to turn to be a vicious animal and they're still wants to keep it I won't really
admit it's it would be very difficult for somebody to be able to keep that in the city when it's in my
own but in order to address that issue one of the things that they have to do is it has to be
and the identification it's been so long since I've looked at it and it's like a hundred
dollars a year in this and you know it costs them a feed to keep that dog get asked to have this there is a whole
section chip and I'll change this to my approach yes so that we that's the same dog if it
doesn't come back to this and we do have a chip reader that we do check for chips and things like that and
it says in here like it's a whole section it starts on page 12 and it goes to page 13 and he sets it out he
did he went through and said I got very well if there's it if someone wants to keep a vicious animal here's
what you've got to do and we have the right to go inspect it with this woman so it doesn't make it a little
easier to track them and pay attention to while we're talking about dogs I just I have I'm looking through
and especially the temperature that's and we've run into here recently there's something in there that
if if homeowners leave their dogs without that's comfortable to have shelter for you more
okay you have animal cruelty this one is one is one is one is a fallen or buildings for animals or is that
fallen or animal cruelty I didn't mean to put you on the spot I just want to make sure that that is
and he is as much of an issue as cold in the water and we have it over there
of abandoning, we've got constocation, treatment, and treatment, and care, and animals.
Right there, um, special muscle food, first pop, we're drinking water, medical attention
to relief, from suffering, shelter to allow, and it goes through, it tells you what the
shelter has to be, um, one of the things that I don't probably about six months ago is that
there requires you to have straw or blanket in there, and for a short time, it's a time,
is that how it is if a dog's out, for sure, and creates a time.
You have a dog that's tenor, if a dog, an animal is tenor, which means, unfortunately, it's
it's chained out.
A dog is an offense that's eight by eight.
Right, if a dog is an animal's tenor, they have to be released every 12 hours, of course,
a certain period of time, and it, it, it, it, it talks about a collar, um, that it has to be ten
good, but he went through and, you know, a really good job of fixing what we have now.
And, uh, you asked about ferrets.
I just do that, because I knew that was the topic of the lifestyle of intersting, and doing
research on this.
I found that the state law requires ferrets to be vaccinated for rabies, and our current ordinance
does not require that.
So, uh, just trying to have consistency between the state law and our ordinance.
So, if there are any ferrets, owners that are listening, they just need to be aware of that.
Do we have a host to you to prove out of the form of like the motion?
We have a second.
Okay.
Roll ball.
Question.
Hi.
Johnson.
For a start.
Sure.
Hi.
Thank you.
147.
didn't know.
Board member box.
For social Lots of Box 71,兄.
Yeah.
These are property set.
Look dang belong to corrupted and second years ago.
Actually 2001, there were houses on means, and shocked at houses on is lux.
So, today I was a little Darva, sut 16 thousand dollars or so to have the houses removed to
in that mean the file on the property in this last June these were lots that in that
percent in the county cell that property cell that they do and because of the wind of
it a bit on them. We couldn't find anybody wondering.
And so we decided to take the opportunity to take those properties back and market those
as an economic development opportunity. The city would have it and be able to promote it for
economic development and get that information to see if the mind of regional chamber and.
that you'll know that this would be through the spot and have some industrial.
So, I'm called beginner.
Yeah.
I think there's lots of possibilities around it.
There's also, there's been plans to do work on the truck route.
So, you're having that route that might require us to have more instruments and things like that.
There's a lot of stuff around it.
That's the location of exactly three.
There was actually more lots there.
And over time it's all been smashed together.
We can warn address is 270.
So, Christine is the county currently on those and they're leaving them to us.
Yeah.
She's at the hospital.
That's what's happening legally.
Yeah.
Contact it.
Russell and said, hey, do you guys don't have plans for that property?
That's the property that the city would like to have and be able to market it.
Christine, I don't know if we're actually going to be real working with.
We're just expanding those arson's work.
Originally considered to be that might get considered for something like that in future days.
So, if I didn't want to be, you know, someone will be having a housing or something as well.
So, Chris, you can you point out where the truck route is actually.
I'm going to make sure I'm going to go away and do that.
Right.
Okay.
So that is the truck route.
It is from each other truck route.
This is the truck route.
It is the truck route.
The ground really is there.
Any of the old, any of the old feeds.
So, the old cable office was right.
It's on that.
That's me.
Okay.
Next one.
I'll ask you.
Okay.
That way.
Then this is out of the sun.
Okay.
Questions?
Motion to approve?
Yeah.
Second.
Question.
process of researching, getting it, making it viable for them.
They came the realization, which we know that the utilities run, that all the properties
located on C at some point, it was decided to connect.
They're one of the utilities that are substituted to go through the property called B, and
it runs through the prep wrap here.
So all of these properties in order to then they have sewage and water.
They got to connect through here, which then requires them to get easements and go through these things.
Yards and then into that kind of being a cumbersome issue at the same time.
But we had our key to the property, probably in the end.
At the same time, we had worked with the way that O227F Northwest.
There were two really bad houses.
And we came to you guys and asked about the O227F
And so that probably is the one that actually took place in this property.
And it came as two of the root 66 landing houses right there together on F.
And we told them that we all couldn't even take this property back and then try to figure out.
So my question for Chris today was, is part of the requirement for root 66 landing was, they built 21.
18.
I mean single family dwellings within a mile within a half mile.
And so we were getting this lot back.
My question was, what did they fulfill the requirement?
And she did, because again, they, the lots on F street helped them meet that requirement.
And so now this is just a very, a lot that they don't really have an interest in.
Well, yeah, they don't need.
And really, the T27F northeast lot is better a lot.
We just couldn't track down the owner of that property.
And it ended up at the end of the day they were able to track them down also.
They just still brought it by mine.
They're people just either drive off and freaking out.
It's just a story of my life.
Yeah.
So yeah.
There's land all over America.
I would say that one of the things that we talked about with the properties on C that have that issue,
when we come up with a vacant lot, and this is something that we would try to do.
What would the owners on each side, and see if that, if they might be interested in the property,
it'd save us from having to mow it and maintain, this is a code issue, a lot anyway.
Right.
So with benefit to city and with the challenges of developing it, if the owners on either side,
both that little one of them were interested in taking that lot and expanding their yard,
it would benefit us in the long run.
So that's any loss that we come up with like that that's part of what we're trying to do.
It's really cost prohibited for somebody to develop that because of the utilities.
It would be a challenge for me.
Yes.
They have to really, really look to the house.
Any more questions for Christie on item 22?
Do we have a motion to approve?
Right.
And I'll check it.
We'll call it.
Forster.
Western Johnson.
Shots.
I, in the last one, poverty at 205, I street, Christy.
Yeah, so this is a property.
It's actually kind of give you a frame of reference.
That's Sivo, it's running east to west.
Since I've taken this job, I've got to really get it my way.
So that Sivo is the main street.
They're running east to west.
And the red rectangle is 25, I.
The property in front of that, running up at Sivo,
is the loves that can be a source.
So that gives you an idea of where this property is located.
This property is around the area that the city already owns several locks in there that
when it's during the 2000 or whatever front.
Yeah, that the city got those properties that they own.
This is a lot that has said, you know, the owners of it can't develop it
because it would have to be elevated to feed or so that putting things on it.
They don't live here in Miami anymore.
And it's an issue for a, we usually have to always send the letters
and from a kind of standpoint to maintain it to maintain the property.
So going ahead and taking that property allows us to keep it hang on to it.
With the work that we're doing on Sivo and Sivo and Sivo and Sivo and Sivo,
it's a property then that we can put on our regular rotation.
The coalition, the movement, the regular way to care of it,
also work with the owners of the properties that, you know,
biting up to it and say, hey, you know, it doesn't.
They, it's not going to do anything to increase their property value per say because it's in the
the blood zone that's seeding.
You know, somebody there might want it to be a spated factory.
Any questions?
We have motion.
And second.
Second.
Low call.
Johnson.
Western.
Forster.
All right.
Sof.
Thank you, Chris.
We actually received the feedback.
No, we haven't.
And I think it's a little bit too much.
I'm going to call it a little bit too much.
I know that you have to do more of that property.
And you probably know which one we have.
Great.
Just mull it, you know.
You need more of them, though.
Just mull.
Okay.
That takes us to, I'm 24.
Election resolution, CC201, 801 calling for proclaiming in order and non-partition
general election.
And the city of Miami County of Ottawa, state of Oklahoma on Tuesday, April 3, 2018,
from the purpose of electing the council members for award three south-west,
and for award four south-east, it's that time of year again.
We have candidates.
I don't either.
I guess we'll find that. Do we have most children pretty early on? I just would like to note that I was looking at them because I thought North East was in 2018
When I read that band, I was also surprised because I thought my memory of it was that
Vicki didn't have to run when we adopted the new chart.
So you're in my last year? It was in my last year. It's been that long since we adopted it.
It was a visual last year. Everything she did after.
Okay, so this is the regular cycle then for that award.
Yes, probably.
What did you just double say?
Not that I don't know what else to be open.
Do you just do it, trust me?
I probably trust you as a member better than mine.
You think for a motion mayor? Yes, I'll make motion.
Second, roll ball.
Western, forster, Johnson, soft.
Hi, other new business, if any.
Hey.
Benjamin, any new business?
That's the business.
Staff reports you're in your packet.
A married council announcements.
Yes.
I don't have to ask them.
I don't think.
This might have been green.
We're getting smart circuit.
Third, believe that Friday night.
Then you probably don't remember of the show.
It's the branch of the big shoulder that band.
Other than what is it says Friday.
Good luck.
That's what they're on Friday night.
And a back to the reunion.
It will be Saturday.
This is Friday.
Friday, March 2nd.
So I think the band is going to be on Friday night.
It says reunion concerts Saturday, March 3rd.
At the Colman.
Which has got time to verify that.
And we'll have to be on the city's website.
Be sure to put that on Facebook or something.
Yeah.
You can be the one.
Okay.
Any other comments on that or anything else?
Oh, just one.
There won't be a good opportunity.
It's a good opportunity.
So anybody's welcome to comment.
Yeah.
It won't be a formally a good rich shot.
Second.
Senator, whatever.
Okay.
City manager, communication, state.
I have that number.
Thanks a lot.
First of all.
I don't know if any of you know this.
That.
It's working in the year.
We put it out.
You just want to try to do it in your report.
And you do one.
You put it in your report.
You do one.
So when that.
Flex does.
Good weather.
But.
This has helped.
We put it out of Facebook.
And I just had a bit of a different.
I don't know if it's on Facebook.
It's active.
It means that.
to a place this year.
And if you have a chance that you haven't built that kind of table up there,
there's done very, very well.
And I think it's just, you know, since even though we're in the middle of our fiscal year,
we're going to be able to tell you here.
Now, I think it's not just a big project,
recognize all of our staff members and everything that they do,
on any of the basis for community.
I mean, it's very, very kind of heartwarming,
sometimes you see what we've been able to accomplish.
And I also wanted to thank you in the program.
My sister for putting you in the program.
Just kind of say hey, here's an idea.
She execute it very, very well.
So that's the email we've been getting.
Yeah.
So they, I think they just turned out very well,
so I think it's just reflects.
And it's just an opportunity to thank everybody that's sitting here,
for everything that they do on any basis.
It's remarkable what we can get done.
And what are those things that we've got done?
Before you move on, Melinda,
I think that would be great than you spent for two.
I thought about that when I saw that.
So I really think it would be nice to do.
We didn't hear you use articles,
but it would be nice for people to see this.
And so a lot, a lot of positive things happen.
Yeah.
I like it.
And if you want to re-tweet them or something like that,
it would be important to have you.
I think that I'll talk to you.
Thank you.
A lot of times, I think we kind of work off of each other.
It's really great.
It's just amazing how social media has become such a great way to communicate with people.
And what I was really appreciative of,
but for example, we were thinking,
okay, what are we going to do when we post about streets?
Because that's what we always get our comments on.
I think it was done in such a way that everybody in your stance is exactly
not only what we have accomplished,
but what we intend to accomplish in this couple of years
that we've done.
So it's kind of a good way to take care of that.
So we've given that there we go.
Something we just accomplished,
my Emma is now a certified, nothing business,
but a state of open life.
We've done that certification,
Kim's been working very hard on that program.
And when we just got that notification just before the end of the year.
And I think there'll be a recognition of a publicity coming up
in the March that we'll let you know about that.
That comes up that we're going to recognize that.
And a lot of the policies that everything did not
has to do with the proof and a lot of thank you for that.
And now we're working toward the certified health community.
This is one of that.
Kim, due to the note-to-back, is that you have to go that route
to get me to borrow the piece of it.
And then that eventually will give us a eligible form of
some fairly large grants that we're going to be able to get,
probably the grants we're going to be able to get,
we're going to be able to get four of things that we've got
to have to see if we can get a part of it.
So it's very positive that.
I just wanted to thank Kim.
She said, hey, please let us know,
but Kim would very hard on this.
Kim staff.
It's, I think.
a lot of kudos with that. Speaking of something you've all been working on, I figured you might
ask this, so I just thought I'd be ready for it with Alicia Snell, but I put a data on the splash
pad. The submissions for ARC text was December 22nd, we had five submissions.
GH2, Mark and Lentland, Patent and EDG. Alicia's put together a committee, and I think they're going
to get together next Monday or Tuesday to review and start developing some recommendations.
I want us to get the presentations to the City Council at our next meeting on January 16th.
And if everything goes well there, we'll be at the process underway and we're still
aiming for a mid-summer completion of this project. So we're getting them to grasp, Patron.
I think that we have been working very much with Susan Henry, who's got a little grant.
He mowed with had some of the slowdowns, because he would pitch her in all of that. Susan Sin,
was indicating the project is an absolute innovation, a cancellation, and less we'd all
go away to December 29th, so we did a statement that was saying, let me be coming in, of course,
those that we've got a decent trust in. So I'm still looking forward to getting that. The final thing is
the knowledge policy. I remember when we had some preliminary discussion, and we were going to be putting
Matt Braves in to talk, take a look at kind of the next steps on the stadium that we're talking
about the honors class, and Matt will not be able to be here until the end of this month. And we decided that
Matt still thinks for the time, it's just what we're going to be saying. So that would probably be your
steady session. I think we'll have to add it on. I think a lot of council members have just questions
about just exactly what we were trying to accomplish. The other will have some information about
the public, which is size and cost and all that, a lot of information for you at that point. But
I think originally we thought we could bring the team on the 16th, but now schedule the size of you
we can't get here until our studies such. So that'll be it in the month. So that's where I'm going to go.
The question for me, the 29 is exactly a session for 25 O S 3 O 7 D 4, the confidential communication
is that the CD is turning up and the serving of the stadium is going to be wet. The CD of my
I am free to close GRDA and GRDA. Then you have something to have. I do. There would be my recommendations
that this would best be discussed in executive session. So I'm recommending it. So we have motion.
You're going to executive session? I'm going to executive session in a second. Second.